In the previous video, we talked
在上一个视频中，我们讨论了（字幕翻译：中国海洋大学，王玺）
about the photo OCR pipeline and how that worked.
OCR管道及其工作原理
In which we would take an image
在OCR管道中我们可以取一张图
and pass the image  Through a
（pass the image，不懂）通过
sequence of machine learning
一系列的机器学习
components in order to
组件来
try to read the text that appears in an image.
尝试读取图片上的文字
In this video I like to tell
今天的视频里，我打算讲
A little bit more about how the
多一点关于流水线
individual components of the pipeline works.
的每个组件的工作原理
In particular most of this video will center around the discussion.
特别的，本视频将会把重点放在讨论
of whats called a sliding windows.
滑动窗口上
The first stage
滤波的
of the filter was the
第一步是
Text detection where we look
确定文字位置，例如我们现在
at an image like this and try
看到的这一幅图片，尝试去
to find the regions of text that appear in this image.
找到图片中文字出现的区域
Text detection is an unusual problem in computer vision.
文字识别对于计算机来说，是一个不寻常的问题
Because depending on the length
因为根据你要尝试
of the text you're trying to
找到的文字的长度
find, these rectangles that you're
这些你要寻找的矩形
trying to find can have different aspect ratios
具有不同的长宽比例
So in order to talk
所以为了讲述如何
about detecting things in images
在图片中发现事物
let's start with a simpler example
我们首先从一个简单点的例子开始
of pedestrian detection and we'll then later go back to apply
即行人检测，然后我们讲如何将
Ideas that were developed
行人检测中的思路用到
in pedestrian detection and apply them to text detection.
文字识别中去
So in pedestrian detection you want
在行人检测中
to take an image that looks
你取一张类似这样的图片
like this and find the
目的就是寻找
individual pedestrians that appear in the image.
图片中的行人
So there's one pedestrian that we
我们找到一个人，
found, there's a second
两个，
one, a third one a fourth one, a fifth one.
三个，四个，五个
And a sixth one.
六个
This problem is maybe slightly
这个问题与文字识别相比，
simpler than text detection just
简单的地方在于：
for the reason that the aspect
你要识别的东西
ratio of most pedestrians are pretty similar.
具有相似的长宽比
Just using a fixed aspect
仅仅使用一个固定
ratio for these rectangles that we're trying to find.
的长宽比就基本可以了
So by aspect ratio I mean
aspect ratio意思是
the ratio between the height and the width of these rectangles.
矩形的高度和宽度之比
They're all the same.
它们都是一样的
for different pedestrians but for
对于不同的行人来说，但是
text detection the height
对于文字来说
and width ratio is different
不同行的文字
for different lines of text
具有不同的比例
Although for pedestrian detection, the
对于行人检测，尽管行人距离
pedestrians can be different distances
摄像头的距离可能
away from the camera and
不同，因此
so the height of these rectangles
矩形的高度
can be different depending on how far away they are.
不一致
but the aspect ratio is the same.
但比例还是维持不变的
In order to build a pedestrian
为了建立一个行人检测系统
detection system here's how you can go about it.
你需要这么做
Let's say that we decide to
例如我们决定要
standardize on this aspect
使用82*36的比例
ratio of 82 by 36
来进行标准化
and we could
当然我们也可以
have chosen some rounded number
选择一些近似的数字
like 80 by 40 or something, but 82 by 36 seems alright.
比如80*40，但82*36看上去是可行的
What we would do is then go
我们将要做的是
out and collect large training sets of positive and negative examples.
出去搜集一些正例和反例
Here are examples of 82
这里有一些
X 36 image patches that do
符合比例的图片
contain pedestrians and here are
以及一些不符合比例
examples of images that do not.
的图片
On this slide I show 12
在这个幻灯片里我展示了12个
positive examples of y=1
正例，用y=1表示
and 12 examples of y=0.
12个反例用y=0表示
In a more typical pedestrian detection
在一个更典型的行人检测应用中，
application, we may have
我们可以会有
anywhere from a 1,000 training
从1000
examples up to maybe
到10000
10,000 training examples, or
个数目的例子，或者
even more if you can
更多，如果你能够
get even larger training sets.
获取到更大的训练集合
And what you can do, is then train
然后，你可以
in your network or some
在你的网络中训练，或者使用
other learning algorithm to
其他学习算法
take this input, an image
来接收这个输入，一个82*36
patch of dimension 82 by
的小图块
36, and to classify  'y'
来划分y
and to classify that image patch
来划分每个图块是否
as either containing a pedestrian or not.
包含一个行人
So this gives you a way
So 这给了你一个
of applying supervised learning in
应用监督学习的方法
order to take an image
来对一个图块进行处理
patch can determine whether or not a pedestrian appears in that image capture.
判断其是否包含有行人
Now, lets say we get
现在，假设我们得到
a new image, a test set
一个新的图片，一个测试集合
image like this and we
图片（类似这个）
want to try to find a pedestrian's picture image.
我们尝试寻找一个行人的图片
What we would do is start
我们首先
by taking a rectangular patch of this image.
在图片中选取一个矩形块
Like that shown up here, so
像这里标注的，
that's maybe a 82 X
例如这是图片中的一个
36 patch of this image,
82*36的图块
and run that image patch through
在我们的分类器里
our classifier to determine whether
运行这个图块，验证
or not there is a
是否图块中
pedestrian in that image patch,
是否有行人
and hopefully our classifier will
期望我们的分类器返回
return y equals 0 for that patch, since there is no pedestrian.
0或者1，对应是否有行人
Next, we then take that green
接下来，我们将
rectangle and we slide it
绿色矩形
over a bit and then
滑动一点
run that new image patch
然后通过
through our classifier to decide if there's a pedestrian there.
我们的分类器来决定是否有行人。
And having done that, we then
完成后，我们
slide the window further to the
滑动窗口向右
right and run that patch
再次
through the classifier again.
运行分类器
The amount by which you shift
每次矩形
the rectangle over each time
移动距离
is a parameter, that's sometimes
是一个参数，有时
called the step size of the
称之为步长
parameter, sometimes also called
有时也被称为
the slide parameter, and if
滑动参数，如果
you step this one pixel at a time.
你一次移动一个像素
So you can use the step size
所以你可以使用步长
or stride of 1, that usually
为1，通常
performs best, but is
表现最好，但
more computational  expensive, and
计算成本较高，如果
so using a step size of
使用步长
maybe 4 pixels at a
为4像素
time, or eight pixels at a
或8像素
time or some large number of
或一些更大的数
pixels might be more common,
可能更常见
since you're then moving the
因为你每次
rectangle a little bit
你移动的距离
more each time.
可以更大
So, using this process, you continue
所以，使用这个程序，你继续
stepping the rectangle over to
向右移动矩形
the right a bit at a
每次一点点距离
time and running each of
然后运行分类器
these patches through a classifier,
对图块进行分类
until eventually, as you
直到最后，随着
slide this window over the
你在图片的不同位置
different locations in the image,
滑动这个矩形
first starting with the first
首先从第一行
row and then we
然后我们
go further rows in
滑动到下一行
the image, you would
你使用某个某个步长
then run all of
对这些不同的图块
these different image patches at
应用某个步长
some step size or some
通过分类器
stride through your classifier.
进行分类
Now, that was a pretty
现在，这是一个相当
small rectangle, that would only
小的矩形，这只会
detect pedestrians of one specific size.
检测一个特定大小的行人。
What we do next is
接下来我们做什么
start to look at larger image patches.
开始使用更大的图块
So now let's take larger images
现在让我们以更大的图片
patches, like those shown here
块，如图
and run those through the classifier as well.
然后也通过分类器运行
And by the way when I say
当我说
take a larger image patch, what
以较大的图块，
I really mean is when you
我的意思是当你
take an image patch like this,
选取这样的图块，
what you're really doing is taking
你真正做的是
that image patch, and resizing
选择图像块，并调整大小
it down to 82 X 36, say.
下降到82×36，
So you take this larger
所以你拿这个更大的
patch and re-size it to
块和调整其大小
be a smaller image and then
成为更小的图，然后
the smaller re-sized image
用这个图块
that is what you
在分类器中
would pass through your classifier to try and decide if there is a pedestrian in that patch.
运行，然后决定是否有行人。
And finally you can do
最后你可以
this at an even larger
在一个更大
scales and run
规模做这一步
that side of Windows to
运行滑动窗口知直到
the end And after
结束，经过
this whole process hopefully your algorithm
这个过程，希望你的算法
will detect whether theres pedestrian
将检测到是否有行人
appears in the image, so
在图中出现，所以
thats how you train a
这就是你如何训练一个
the classifier, and then
分类器，然后
use a sliding windows classifier,
使用滑动窗口分类，
or use a sliding windows detector in
或使用一个滑动窗口检测器
order to find pedestrians in the image.
去寻找图像中的行人。
Let's have a turn to the
让我们转向
text detection example and talk
文本检测的例子，讨论
about that stage in our
那个阶段，在我们
photo OCR pipeline, where our
的照片OCR管道，我们
goal is to find the text regions in unit.
的目标是找到一个个的文本区域。
similar to pedestrian detection you
与行人检测类似，你
can come up with a label
能拿到具有标签的
training set with positive examples
的正例集合
and negative examples with examples
和负例集合
corresponding to regions where text appears.
对应文字出现的区域
So instead of trying to detect pedestrians, we're now trying to detect texts.
所以不再进行行人检测，我们现在尝试检测文本。
And so positive examples are going
正面的样本是
to be patches of images where there is text.
具有文字的图块
And negative examples is going
负面的样本是
to be patches of images where there isn't text.
没有文字的
Having trained this we can
训练完之后我们
now apply it to a
可以将其应用到
new image, into a test
新的图片上，一个测试集
set image.
图片
So here's the image that we've been using as example.
这是我们作为例子的图片
Now, last time we run,
现在，上次我们运行
for this example we are going
这个样本，我们将
to run a sliding windows at
运行一个滑动窗口
just one fixed scale just
在一个固定的比例
for purpose of illustration, meaning that
只是为了进行说明，意味着
I'm going to use just one rectangle size.
我将使用一个矩形的大小。
But lets say I run my little
但如果我
sliding windows classifier on lots
使用这个小的滑动窗口分类器在
of little image patches like
在大量类似这样的小图块上
this if I
如果我
do that, what Ill end
这样做，我将
up with is a result
得到一个结果
like this where the white
像这样，白色
region show where my
区域显示我的
text detection system has found
文本检测系统发现了
text and so the axis' of these two figures are the same.
文本，这两个图的坐标是一样的
So there is a region
有一个这样的区域
up here, of course also
在这里，当然也
a region up here, so the
有一个区域在这里，所以
fact that this black up here
黑色区域
represents that the classifier
表示分类器
does not think it's found any
并不认为它发现
texts up there, whereas the
了文字，而
fact that there's a lot
事实上有很多
of white stuff here, that reflects that
白色，这反映出
classifier thinks that it's found a bunch of texts.
分类器认为发现了一串文本。
over there on the image.
在图上的这个位置
What i have done on this
我在图片左下角
image on the lower left is
做的操作是
actually use white to
其实用白色
show where the classifier thinks it has found text.
显示分类器认为它找到了文字
And different shades of grey
深浅不同的灰色
correspond to the probability that
对应分类器输出
was output by the classifier,
的概率
so like the shades of grey
所以类似灰色阴影
corresponds to where it
对应它
thinks it might have found text
认为它可能找到了文本
but has lower confidence the bright
但是不够确定
white response to whether the classifier,
亮的白色对应
up with a very high
一个很高的
probability, estimated probability of
概率，在那个位置有行人存在
there being pedestrians in that location.
的概率估计
We aren't quite done yet because
我们还没完全结束因为
what we actually want to do
我们真正想做的
is draw rectangles around all
是在所有文字周围
the region where this text
绘制
in the image, so were
矩形，所以
going to take one more step
我们进一步
which is we take the output
输出分类器的
of the classifier and apply
输出和应用
to it what is called an expansion operator.
所谓的膨胀算子
So what that does is, it
那么它所做的是，它
take the image here,
取这里的图，
and it takes each of
它把每个白色块
the white blobs, it takes each
它把每一个
of the white regions and it expands that white region.
白色区域扩大。
Mathematically, the way you
从数学上，你实现它的方式
implement that is, if you
是，如果
look at the image on the right, what
看右边的图像，
we're doing to create the
我们正在创造的
image on the right is, for every
右边的这个图像，对于每一个像素
pixel we are going
我们将要
to ask, is it withing
问，它是否和
some distance of a
左边图中的白色像素
white pixel in the left image.
有一段距离
And so, if a specific pixel
如果是的话，如果一个特定的像素
is within, say, five pixels
距离左边中的
or ten pixels of a white
白色像素，比如
pixel in the leftmost image, then
5个或者10个像素距离，然后
we'll also color that pixel white in the rightmost image.
我们会在右边的图像中，把这个像素也染成白色
And so, the effect of this
这样做的效果是
is, we'll take each of the
把左边图中
white blobs in the leftmost
每个白色区块
image and expand them a
扩大一点
bit, grow them a little
让其增长一点
bit, by seeing whether the
通过检查
nearby pixels, the white pixels,
邻近像素，白色像素
and then coloring those nearby pixels in white as well.
然后把它们也染成白色
Finally, we are just about done.
最后，我们就要完成了
We can now look at this
现在我们可以看看这个
right most image and just
最右边的图像就
look at the connecting components
看连接组件
and look at the as white
看白色
regions and draw bounding boxes around them.
区域，在其周围绘制边框。
And in particular, if we look at
特别的，如果我们看一看
all the white regions, like
所有的白色区域，比如
this one, this one, this
这个，这个，这个
one, and so on, and
，等等
if we use a simple heuristic
如果我们用一个简单的启发式方法
to rule out rectangles whose aspect
来排除那些比例
ratios look funny because we
滑稽的矩形，因为我们
know that boxes around text
知道文本周围的框
should be much wider than they are tall.
应该是宽远大于高
And so if we ignore the
所以如果我们忽略
thin, tall blobs like this one
窄的，高的图块，像这个，
and this one, and
和这一个
we discard these ones because
我们丢弃这些
they are too tall and thin, and
因为它们太高，太窄
we then draw a the rectangles
我们在那些
around the ones whose aspect
比例符合文字的
ratio thats a height
图块周围
to what ratio looks like for
绘制矩形框
text regions, then we
然后我们
can draw rectangles, the bounding
可以绘制矩形，包围
boxes around this text
在这些
region, this text region, and
文字区域，
that text region, corresponding to
分别对应
the Lula B's antique mall logo,
Lula Bs 商场标志，
the Lula B's, and this little open sign.
Lula B，以及这个小“Open”的标志
Of over there.
那边
This example by the actually misses one piece of text.
这个例子中其实遗漏了一段文字
This is very hard to read, but there is actually one piece of text there.
这个不好读取，但事实上那边是有一块文字的
That says [xx] are corresponding
这个[ XX ]对应
to this but the aspect ratio
这个区域，但是纵横比
looks wrong so we discarded that one.
看起来是错误，所以我们丢弃掉
So you know it's ok
所以你知道它是好的
on this image, but in
在这个图中，但在
this particular example the classifier
这个特殊的例子中，分类器
actually missed one piece of text.
遗漏了一段文字。
It's very hard to read because
这是很难读的，因为
there's a piece of text
有一段文字
written against a transparent window.
写在了透明的窗户上
So that's text detection
那么这就是文本检测
using sliding windows.
使用滑动窗口
And having found these rectangles
发现包含文字
with the text in it, we
的矩形，我们
can now just cut out
现在可以切出
these image regions and then
这些图像区域，然后
use later stages of pipeline to try to meet the texts.
使用后期的管道来满足文本。
Now, you recall that the
现在，你回忆一下
second stage of pipeline was
管道的第二步是
character segmentation, so given an
字符分割，所以给一个
image like that shown on top,
如上部所示的图片
how do we segment out the individual characters in this image?
我们如何分割出此图像中的单个字符？
So what we can do is
所以我们所能做的就是
again use a supervised learning
再次使用有监督的学习
algorithm with some set of
算法，以及一些
positive and some set of
正例和反例
negative examples, what were
我们将要做的是
going to do is look in
检查这些
the image patch and try
图像块并且尝试
to decide if there
决定在图块的
is split between two characters
的中间是否存在
right in the middle of that image match.
两个字符的分割
So for initial positive examples.
所以对于初始的正例
This first cross example, this image
第一跨的样本，这个图块
patch looks like the
看起来
middle of it is indeed
中间的确
the middle has splits between two
存在两个字符的分割
characters and the second example
第二例
again this looks like a
仍然看起来像一个
positive example, because if I split
正面的样本，因为如果我
two characters by putting a
在正中间放一条线
line right down the middle, that's the right thing to do.
来分割字符，这样做是正确的。
So, these are positive examples, where
等，这些都是正面的样本，
the middle of the image represents
图像的中间表示
a gap or a split
两个字符之间的
between two distinct characters, whereas
沟壑或分割，而
the negative examples, well, you
负面的样本，很好，你
know, you don't want to split
知道，你不想分裂
two characters right in the
把两个字从中间
middle, and so
分割，所以
these are negative examples because
这些都是负面的样本，因为
they don't represent the midpoint between two characters.
不代表两个字符之间的中点。
So what we will do
所以我们要做的
is, we will train a classifier,
是：我们会训练一个分类器，
maybe using new network, maybe
也许利用新的网络，也许
using a different learning algorithm, to
使用不同的学习算法，
try to classify between the positive and negative examples.
尝试将正面和负面的样本进行区分。
Having trained such a classifier,
有这样一个分类器的训练，
we can then run this on
我们可以在
this sort of text that our
我们的文字检测系统中
text detection system has pulled out.
分离出的文字上运行这个分类器
As we start by looking at
我们先来看看
that rectangle, and we ask,
那个矩形，我们问，
"Gee, does it look
“哎呀，它看起来
like the middle of
像那个绿色矩形的
that green rectangle, does it
中间？，它
look like the midpoint between two characters?".
看起来像两个字符之间的中点？”。
And hopefully, the classifier will
希望，分类器
say no, then we slide
说不，然后我们滑动
the window over and this
窗户，这是
is a one dimensional sliding
一维的滑动
window classifier, because were
窗口分类器，因为
going to slide the window only
将滑动窗口
in one straight line from
在一条直线上
left to right, theres no different rows here.
从左到右，这时没有不同的行
There's only one row here.
只有一行
But now, with the classifier in
但是，在这个位置时，
this position, we ask, well,
我们使用分类器，我们问，好，
should we split those two characters
我们应该分开这两个字符
or should we put a split right down the middle of this rectangle.
或者我们应该在这个矩形的中间进行分割
And hopefully, the classifier will
希望，分类器
output y equals one, in
输出Y=1，在
which case we will decide to
这种情况下我们会决定
draw a line down there, to try to split two characters.
画一条线在那里，试图分割这两个字符
Then we slide the window over
然后再次滑动窗口
again, classifier says, don't
分类器说，不
close the gap, slide over again,
关闭间隙，再次滑过，
classifier says yes, do split
分类器说yes，进行分割
there and so
等等
on, and we slowly slide the
然后慢慢地滑动
classifier over to the
分类器向
right and hopefully it will
右边，希望它可以将
classify this as another positive example and
这个作为另一个正面的样本，
so on.
等等
And we will slide this window
我们向右滑动每一步
over to the right, running the
运行分类器
classifier at every step, and
希望它可以
hopefully it will tell us,
告诉我们，
you know, what are the right locations
你知道，应该在哪里
to split these characters up into,
对字符进行分割
just split this image up into individual characters.
将这个图像分成单个字符
And so thats 1D sliding
这就是一维滑动
windows for character segmentation.
窗口字符分割
So, here's the overall photo OCR pipe line again.
所以，这里是OCR照片管道的全部
In this video we've talked about
在这段视频中我们已经谈到了
the text detection step, where
文本检测步骤，其中
we use sliding windows to detect text.
我们使用滑动窗口检测文本。
And we also use a one-dimensional
我们也使用一个一维的
sliding windows to do character
滑动窗来做
segmentation to segment out,
字符分割
you know, this text image in division of characters.
你知道，这个文本图像的字符分割。
The final step through the
通过管道的最后一步
pipeline is the character classification
是字符分类
step and that step you might
步骤和这一步你或许
already be much more familiar
更加熟悉
with the early videos
与早期的关于
on supervised learning
监督学习的视频
where you can apply a standard
你可以应用一个标准的
supervised learning within maybe
监督学习也许
on your network or maybe something
在你的网络上或者一些
else in order to
其他的，为了
take it's input, an image
把它的输入，类似
like that and classify which alphabet
这样的图片，将其
or which 26 characters A
分类到26个字母
to Z, or maybe we should
或者36个，
have 36 characters if you
如果包含
have the numerical digits as
数字的话
well, the multi class
多
classification problem where you
分类器问题
take it's input and image
它的输入
contained a character and decide
一个包含文字的图片
what is the character that appears in that image?
出现在图像中的字符是什么？
So that was the photo OCR
那么这就是照片OCR
pipeline and how you can
以及你如何
use ideas like sliding windows
使用滑动窗口
classifiers in order to
分类器来
put these different components to
使用这些不同的组件
develop a photo OCR system.
开发照片OCR系统
In the next few videos we
在接下来的几个视频我们
keep on using the problem of
继续使用照片OCR问题
photo OCR to explore somewhat
探索一些
interesting issues surrounding building an application like this.
有趣的问题，建立类似的应用。